# 冰箱里边晾的差不多了 倍儿柔
It has been chilling in the fridge for quite a while, (look) how smooth and silky it turns out
# 胎菊绿豆爽
Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum
# 绿豆头天晚上搁冰箱里边泡了一宿
Those mung beans have been in the fridge soaking in water since last night
# 天儿热（不放冰箱）容易变质 就麻烦了
Mung beans can go bad quite easily in hot weathers, there will be trouble if it is not place in the fridge while rehydrating
# 胎菊提前（用开水）泡一小时
Those chrysanthemums were soaked in hot water for an hour in advance
# 您今天选这食材特别好
You picked some real good ingredients today
# 让人家心情静下来 你知为什么
It can give people a calm and relaxing mood after consuming, do you know why?
# 03年我 在小汤山的时候
When I was at Xiao Tangshan back in 2003
# 每天要喝一顿绿豆粥 解毒
I will drink some mung bean congee every day to cleanse my body
# 水开了 我们把全都搁进去 泡好的豆
The water is boiling now, pour in all the hydrated mung beans
# 我看您那儿还放着碱面呢
I see you have some cooking soda there
# 放不放
Are you going to put some in?
# 放点儿
Let’s put some in
# 大爷就是大爷
Got to listen to Da Ye’s suggestions, he is experienced
# 其实绿豆少放点碱面
Actually, if you add a little soda when cooking mung beans
# 它出来的颜色也漂亮
It gives the mung bean a prettier colour
# 也别太多 就是两克到三克
you do not need too much, 2-3 grams should do the trick
# 然后我们盖上锅盖
Now place the lid on
# 前两期节目我说过这个
I discussed about this 2 shows ago
# 比如熬一锅粥 先放少半锅水
For example, if you are making a pot of congee, you should start with less than half of a pot of water
# 火还不能开太大 给它一个加热时间
Also make sure the heat is not too high, you want to give it some time to come up to temperature
# 一开锅点点儿凉水
Add a little bit of cold water into the pot as soon as it starts to boil
# 通过热胀冷缩 这豆很快就开花
Because heat expand and cold contracts, this will allow the beans to burst from its skin very quickly
# 开了吧 少加点凉水
It is starting to boil now, let’s add a little bit of cold water
# 火可以关小一点 让它慢慢开
You can turn the heat lower, let it boil gently
# 我看有点发浑了
I can see that the water is getting a bit cloudy now
# 说明这豆有开嘴儿的了
This means some mung beans is starting to burst from their skins
# 就慢慢煮着吧别着急
Just let it boil, don’t rush
# 刚强来 掀锅 又加一次 这就差不多了
Gangqiang, open the lid and add some cold water again, this should do it
# 开锅喽 再看看
The mung beans are cooked, have a look
# 这汤留着 冰镇一下多棒 你看开花了
You can keep the poaching liquid, chill it in the fridge and it will be delicious. Look at how the beans burst from their skins
# 先把豆捞出来
Darin out the mung beans first
# 原汤还得留着 你看全张嘴了
We need to keep the poaching liquid. Look, all the beans burst from their skins
# 咱为了提高速度（过凉水）
For time purposes we are running the beans under cold water
# 应该是晾凉
The proper way is to let it cool by itself
# 可以把冰糖放进去了 让它化着
You can add white rock sugar now, let it melt on its own
# 这水就不要了大爷
Da Ye we don’t need to add extra water into the blender
# 少来 要不你转不起来
Just add a little touch, otherwise the blender will have a hard time blending.
# 倒出一盆里头 一会胎菊水搁进去 真棒
Place the puree into a big bowl, we will add the chrysanthemum water later, it will be extraordinary
# 好过箩
Ok, lets pass the puree through the sieve
# 为什么这可以用手你知道吗
Do you know why we can use our hands for this?
# 一会还得加热
Because we are going to heat this up again
# 这可千万别倒 擓两勺熬粥 千万别糟蹋
Do not through this away (thick mung bean paste), you can add two spoons of this when making porridge, please don’t waste it
# 你要是不放冰箱也行
It is alright if you don’t put this (thick mung bean paste) inside a fridge
# 放三天就是麻豆腐了 豆汁也出来了
Let it sit in room temperature for 3 days and you will have fermented bean dregs and fermented bean juice
# 绝对是好东西 真的
This is some really good stuff
# 这可以下锅了
This is ready to go into the wok now
# 大爷你看 胎菊水
Da Ye look, chrysanthemum water
# 大爷都搁里了啊
Da Ye poured all of it into the wok
# 过出这绿豆沙来 下锅还要勾一点芡
After adding the sieved mung bean puree, we still need to add some slurry
# 搁点淀粉或者糯米粉
Add some starch or sticky rice powder
# 不勾芡不行 它沉底儿 融不了
Adding slurry is a must, otherwise all the solid will sink to the bottom and will not mix well together
# 藕粉糯米粉都行
Lotus root powder and stick rice powder both works
# 拢到什么程度就是米汤芡儿
Stir until the soup is at a similar consistency as rice congee
# 这种喝起来就比较柔 比较爽
This kind of consistency is very silky when drinking, very refreshing
# 当我们要冷冻（冷藏）了以后
If we decide refrigerate this
# 它比现在还要稠一些
Its consistency will be a bit thicker
# 藕粉 菱角粉 马蹄粉 糯米粉
Lotus root powder, water caltrop powder, water chestnut powder, sticky rice powder
# 家里有什么都行
Use whatever you got at home
# 倒这盆里就行
This bowl will do
# 先晾晾
Let it cool first
# 冰箱里边晾的差不多了 倍儿柔
It is almost completely cooled being inside the fridge, it became extremely silky
# 胎菊绿豆爽
Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum
# 大爷您尝尝
Da Ye, please have a taste
# 一饮而尽
“finished the entire bowl in one gulp”
# 细腻滑爽
Fine and smooth
# 菊香味浓
It has a strong chrysanthemum flavour
# 喝完这个 给大家降降火
Drink this will help everyone to ease their heatiness
# 降降温 排排毒
Ease the heatiness, Cleansing the body
# 炒拔丝（糖）之前
Before making any syrup coating dish
# 要把原材料都炸好
All the ingredients need to be pre-fried
# 炸成半成品
Fried until it is semi-finished
# 就先定型
so its shape is fixed
# 当糖一入锅的时候
As soon as the sugar goes into the wok
# 同时要把油锅也要升温
Turn up the heat for the deep-frying pan simultaneously
# 等这糖一旦炒好了
When the sugar in the pan is fully melted
# 然后把该炸的原料二次复炸
Start the second frying of the ingredients
# （复）炸完以后
After the ingredients are done frying for the second time
# 这糖色还没炒（好）呢
The sugar will still not yet be fully caramelized
# 要控油（原料）
Drain the oil out of the ingredients
# 等这糖色到这节点上了
Wait until the sugar are fully caramelized
# 迅速的把原料倒入拔丝锅里了
Quickly add the ingredients to the wok with caramelized sugar
# 翻锅的时候要离火
Make sure the wok is not in contact with any heat when tossing
# 一点一点翻
Toss the wok little by little
# 不能翻完了翻匀了
You cannot stop tossing even when all the ingredients are evenly coated with syrup
# 就倒入盘里了也不行
Do not put it into the plate immediately as well
# 翻一翻
Keep tossing
# 让他降低温度
Let the ingredients cool down a little in the wok
# 然后锅底下糖逐渐都包裹在原料上
so all the syrup that are at the bottom of the wok covers the ingredient gradually and evenly
# 这个时候再出盘
Only plate when you reach this stage
# 如果你出盘太早
If you plate too early
# 装到盘里了
As soon as the ingredients goes onto the plate
# 那糖全留到盘底下去了
the syrup will run down from the ingredients and settle all on to the plate
# 原料上没有糖
There will be no sugar left on the ingredients
# 所以要有时候
So sometimes
# 甚至于我们旁边
We can even ask someone to stand next to us
# 还有帮忙的
so they can help us
# 拿个扇子
Grab a fan
# 呼呼扇两下让它降温
Use the fan to make it cool down
# 降温的目的
The purpose of cooling it down
# 让糖均匀的裹在原料上
Is to let the sugar settles on to the ingredient more evenly
# 出来的效果就更好一些
So the end result would be better
# 【国宴大师•胎菊绿豆爽】败火解暑小甜饮——胎菊绿豆爽！细腻丝滑、香甜柔和，夏季养生就靠它！拔丝的制作方法|老饭骨
# [State Banquet Master Chef - Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum] a seasonal sweet drink good for heatiness! Fine and silky, fragrant and sweet. It is all you need to preserve good health in summer.  + How to make syrup coating dish | Lao Fan Gu
# 小友們好！夏日炎炎，老飯骨為大傢伙兒準備了一道敗火解暑的小甜飲——胎菊綠豆爽。
# 這道甜飲做法簡單，口感絲滑細膩，還有著香甜的菊花味兒。
# 這胎菊綠豆爽不僅味道好，還能夠幫助大家清熱解毒。 03年大爺在小湯山的時候每天都要喝一碗綠豆粥！
# 夏天要來上這麼一碗，沁心涼，過癮！
# 片尾還有拔絲的製作方法，想知道如何做好拔絲，小友們可一定要記得觀看！
# Hi Friends! The sun is glaring and the weather is getting hot. Lao Fan Gu have prepared a seasonal sweet drink that can ease the heatiness for everyone - Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum. It is simple to make, fine and silky and it has the sweet aroma of chrysanthemum.
# This dish does not only taste good, but also aids to ease the heatiness. Back in 2003 when Da Ye was at Xiao Tangshan, he will have a bowl of mung bean congee each day. If you have a bowl of this during summer, it will cool your whole body down and will be very satisfying.
# At the end of the video there will be methods on how to make any syrup coating dish. If you want to know how to make syrup coating dishes properly, please remember to give it a watch!
# 冰箱里边晾的差不多了 倍儿柔
It has been chilling in the fridge for quite a while, (look) how smooth and silky it turns out
# 胎菊绿豆爽
Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum
# 绿豆头天晚上搁冰箱里边泡了一宿
Those mung beans have been in the fridge soaking in water since last night
# 天儿热（不放冰箱）容易变质 就麻烦了
Mung bean can go bad quite easily in hot weathers, there will be trouble if it is not place in the fridge while rehydrating
# 胎菊提前（用开水）泡一小时
Those chrysanthemums were soaked in hot water for an hour in advance
# 您今天选这食材特别好
You picked some real good ingredients today
# 让人家心情静下来 你知为什么
It can give people a calm and relaxing mood after consuming, do you know why?
# 03年我 在小汤山的时候
When I was at Xiao Tangshan back in 2003
# 每天要喝一顿绿豆粥 解毒
I will drink some mung bean congee every day to cleanse my body
# 水开了 我们把全都搁进去 泡好的豆
The water is boiling now, pour in all the hydrated mung beans
# 我看您那儿还放着碱面呢
I see you have some cooking soda there
# 放不放
Are you going to put some in?
# 放点儿
Let’s put some in
# 大爷就是大爷
Got to listen to Da Ye’s suggestions, he is experienced
# 其实绿豆少放点碱面
Actually, if you add a little soda when cooking mung beans
# 它出来的颜色也漂亮
It gives the mung bean a prettier colour
# 也别太多 就是两克到三克
you do not need too much, 2-3 grams should do the trick
# 然后我们盖上锅盖
Now place the lid on
# 前两期节目我说过这个
I discussed about this 2 shows ago
# 比如熬一锅粥 先放少半锅水
For example, if you are making a pot of congee, you should start with less than half of a pot of water
# 火还不能开太大 给它一个加热时间
Also make sure the heat is not too high, you want to give it some time to come up to temperature
# 一开锅点点儿凉水
Add a little bit of cold water into the pot as soon as it starts to boil
# 通过热胀冷缩 这豆很快就开花
Because heat expand and cold contracts, this will allow the beans to burst from its skin very quickly
# 开了吧 少加点凉水
It is starting to boil now, let’s add a little bit of cold water
# 火可以关小一点 让它慢慢开
You can turn the heat lower, let it boil gently
# 我看有点发浑了
I can see that the water is getting a bit cloudy now
# 说明这豆有开嘴儿的了
This means some mung beans is starting to burst from their skins
# 就慢慢煮着吧别着急
Just let it boil, don’t rush
# 刚强来 掀锅 又加一次 这就差不多了
Gangqiang, open the lid and add some cold water again, this should do it
# 开锅喽 再看看
The mung beans are cooked, have a look
# 这汤留着 冰镇一下多棒 你看开花了
You can keep the poaching liquid, chill it in the fridge and it will be delicious. Look at how the beans burst from their skins
# 先把豆捞出来
Darin out the mung beans first
# 原汤还得留着 你看全张嘴了
We need to keep the poaching liquid. Look, all the beans burst from their skins
# 咱为了提高速度（过凉水）
For time purposes we are running the beans under cold water
# 应该是晾凉
The proper way is to let it cool by itself
# 可以把冰糖放进去了 让它化着
You can add white rock sugar now, let it melt on its own
# 这水就不要了大爷
Da Ye we don’t need to add extra water into the blender
# 少来 要不你转不起来
Just add a little touch, otherwise the blender will have a hard time blending.
# 倒出一盆里头 一会胎菊水搁进去 真棒
Place the puree into a big bowl, we will add the chrysanthemum water later, it will be extraordinary
# 好过箩
Ok, lets pass the puree through the sieve
# 为什么这可以用手你知道吗
Do you know why we can use our hands for this?
# 一会还得加热
Because we are going to heat this up again
# 这可千万别倒 擓两勺熬粥 千万别糟蹋
Do not through this away (thick mung bean paste), you can add two spoons of this when making porridge, please don’t waste it
# 你要是不放冰箱也行
It is alright if you don’t put this (thick mung bean paste) inside a fridge
# 放三天就是麻豆腐了 豆汁也出来了
Let it sit in room temperature for 3 days and you will have fermented bean dregs and fermented bean juice
# 绝对是好东西 真的
This is some really good stuff
# 这可以下锅了
This is ready to go into the wok now
# 大爷你看 胎菊水
Da Ye look, chrysanthemum water
# 大爷都搁里了啊
Da Ye poured all of it into the wok
# 过出这绿豆沙来 下锅还要勾一点芡
After adding the sieved mung bean puree, we still need to add some slurry
# 搁点淀粉或者糯米粉
Add some starch or sticky rice powder
# 不勾芡不行 它沉底儿 融不了
Adding slurry is a must, otherwise all the solid will sink to the bottom and will not mix well together
# 藕粉糯米粉都行
Lotus root powder and stick rice powder both works
# 拢到什么程度就是米汤芡儿
Stir until the soup is at a similar consistency as rice congee
# 这种喝起来就比较柔 比较爽
This kind of consistency is very silky when drinking, very refreshing
# 当我们要冷冻（冷藏）了以后
If we decide refrigerate this
# 它比现在还要稠一些
Its consistency will be a bit thicker
# 藕粉 菱角粉 马蹄粉 糯米粉
Lotus root powder, water caltrop powder, water chestnut powder, sticky rice powder
# 家里有什么都行
Use whatever you got at home
# 倒这盆里就行
This bowl will do
# 先晾晾
Let it cool first
# 冰箱里边晾的差不多了 倍儿柔
It is almost completely cooled being inside the fridge, it became extremely silky
# 胎菊绿豆爽
Mung bean soup seasoned with chrysanthemum
# 大爷您尝尝
Da Ye, please have a taste
# 一饮而尽
“finished the entire bowl in one gulp”
# 细腻滑爽
Fine and smooth
# 菊香味浓
It has a strong chrysanthemum flavour
# 喝完这个 给大家降降火
Drink this will help everyone to ease their heatiness
# 降降温 排排毒
Ease the heatiness, Cleansing the body
# 炒拔丝（糖）之前
Before making any syrup coating dish
# 要把原材料都炸好
All the ingredients need to be pre-fried
# 炸成半成品
Fried until it is semi-finished
# 就先定型
so its shape is fixed
# 当糖一入锅的时候
As soon as the sugar goes into the wok
# 同时要把油锅也要升温
Turn up the heat for the deep-frying pan simultaneously
# 等这糖一旦炒好了
When the sugar in the pan is fully melted
# 然后把该炸的原料二次复炸
Start the second frying of the ingredients
# （复）炸完以后
After the ingredients are done frying for the second time
# 这糖色还没炒（好）呢
The sugar will still not yet be fully caramelized
# 要控油（原料）
Drain the oil out of the ingredients
# 等这糖色到这节点上了
Wait until the sugar are fully caramelized
# 迅速的把原料倒入拔丝锅里了
Quickly add the ingredients to the wok with caramelized sugar
# 翻锅的时候要离火
Make sure the wok is not in contact with any heat when tossing
# 一点一点翻
Toss the wok little by little
# 不能翻完了翻匀了
You cannot stop tossing even when all the ingredients are evenly coated with syrup
# 就倒入盘里了也不行
Do not put it into the plate immediately as well
# 翻一翻
Keep tossing
# 让他降低温度
Let the ingredients cool down a little in the wok
# 然后锅底下糖逐渐都包裹在原料上
so all the syrup that are at the bottom of the wok covers the ingredient gradually and evenly
# 这个时候再出盘
Only plate when you reach this stage
# 如果你出盘太早
If you plate too early
# 装到盘里了
As soon as the ingredients goes onto the plate
# 那糖全留到盘底下去了
the syrup will run down from the ingredients and settle all on to the plate
# 原料上没有糖
There will be no sugar left on the ingredients
# 所以要有时候
So sometimes
# 甚至于我们旁边
We can even ask someone to stand next to us
# 还有帮忙的
so they can help us
# 拿个扇子
Grab a fan
# 呼呼扇两下让它降温
Use the fan to make it cool down
# 降温的目的
The purpose of cooling it down
# 让糖均匀的裹在原料上
Is to let the sugar settles on to the ingredient more evenly
# 出来的效果就更好一些
So the end result would be better